Abhigith Neil Abraham

Puthenkandathil house, Manakkappady, Karumalloor P.O, Aluva, Ernakulam, Kerala, India, 683511

📕+91.7907752461 | 💌 abhijithneilabrahampk@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/abhijithneilabraham | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/abhijith-neil-abraham-765165141/

Personal Profile

Machine Learning Research Engineer with 2 years of experience in ML research and ML software development. I have an excellent experience in ML Tooling, Model Deployment and DevOps. I have helped dozens of enterprises in builling and scaling ML applications. I have contributed to open source and have authored and contributed to several tools in the ML space. I believe in working in a community-like workplace where greatness is achieved

Education

College of Engineering, Trivandrum

Trivandrum, India

BTech in Electrical and Electronics

August 2016 - June 2020

Graduated with 8.1 CGPA on a scale of 10

Work Experience _____

Autonomio Helsinki, Finland

Machine Learning Engineer

Feb 2022 - Present

- · Authored and Open Sourced Jako, a distributed computing tool for hyperparameter optimisation using multiple machines.
- · Authored and Open sourced EasyEnergy, a tool to track carbon emissions and energy draw for Machine Learning Experiments
- Technical Skills: Python with PyTorch, Tensorflow, Pandas, Ubuntu Linux, Linux tools, Apt, Scripting, Git, Docker, SQL, Postgres, AWS, GCP.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills.

Saama Chennai, India

Machine Learning Research Engineer

Dec 2020 - June 2022

- · Worked with the Research team for innovating impact of machine learning with natural language processing in Clinical Domain
- Wrote Research papers(under review) for NLP tasks such as Question Summarisation and Bio Sentence Transformers.
- Built and deployed novel research models to huggingface
- · Worked with internal software research team to build tools to automate cross matching of medical domain databases.
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow, Pytorch, Algorithmic Research, Natural Language Processing, Git.
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

Minicog Kochi, India

Machine Learning Engineer

May 2020 - Dec 2020

- Built an open source tool named TableQA for querying natural language on tabular data
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow, Pytorch, SQL, Natural Language Processing, Git.

Research Publications __

- Research paper TableQuery: Querying tabular data with natural language
- Research Journal Deep Learning Applications with Python
- Technical Skills: Tableau, Overleaf, LaTeX.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

Skills

Programming Python (Tensorflow, PyTorch, Pandas, Scikit-learn. etc.), SQL, Postgres, Docker, Git, AWS, GCP.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), LTFX(Overleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Microsoft Office, Firebase, Hasura, Metabase.

Community Management, People Relationship, Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging **Soft Skills**

Presentation.

Languages

English Professional proficiency Hindi Professional proficiency Malayalam Native proficiency

SEPTEMBER 27, 2022